the internet was the digitization of
ideas and
information. And right now, uh, you
know, Bitcoin and this digital asset
world, we're digitizing value and money.
That's got to be the biggest investment
theme of all time over the next 10
years. I think Bitcoin can get to a
million. Bitcoin, I've never seen
anything like this in the investment
world. This asset the bitcoin and I'll
call it broadly the digital asset
ecosystem last 10 12 years is the single
best performing asset in the history of
assets. There's no financial ass there's
no asset ever that is up as much as
bitcoin is the last 10 years last 12
years the NASDAQ which has done pretty
well is down 99.9% against bitcoin. What
is holding the institution back? because
they they can see it's the best
performing asset. I think all the
traditional assets, bonds, stocks,
currencies, commodities, um real estate,
everything that's in traditional world
and gold is in that world and gold is a
hedge against you know certain macro
scenarios developing. You want to have
some gold in your portfolio in your
traditional portfolio. Bitcoin to me can
be thought of as a hedge against the
entire traditional world including gold
in it. Bitcoin and the digital asset
world is really the only interesting
thing to be doing. If you understand
store of value and gold as a currency,
it's not that far a leap to understand
Bitcoin. We're going to have a 100
billion robots in 10 years. people are
going to have to start to think about
what to do with all of the time that
they have that like we're approaching
some you know metaphysical moment in
human history where you know the level
of wealth and will be so high that
services and goods will be almost cost
almost nothing and he says the real
challenge for people will be what to do
with themselves if you look at the
future you want to be in the middle of
the most liquid deepest market but
people are not talking about it people
just don't care I know I Go get it.
[Music]
Claim the fame. If you want success,
then take a look away.
Hi Dan.
Hey Bonnie. Good to see you.
I'm super excited to talk to you because
you have a very interesting path. So
from macro to gold to crypto. So how did
your experience in gold and the old
world asset help you understand Bitcoin
better? Yeah, I mean I I almost think
how could how could you ever take
another path? Meaning to get to to
understand the macro first lets you
understand about broader let's just say
monetary developments in general, right?
And so of course if you're involved in
the macro markets uh gold is used to be
the anchor but gold is a you know very
heavily traded commodity
um and of course the traditional 5,000
year old store value. So if you
understand store of value and gold as a
currency
um it's not that far a leap to
understand Bitcoin as a store of value
and a currency. It is a cryptocurrency.
It's just the a digital form. And the
fact that of course that it was scarce,
21 million only, that made it easy. What
made Bitcoin really hard was the tech
behind it. So I understood why you know
it was a store of value for the digital
world but understanding how you know
blockchains work how the proofof work
algorithm actually works reading the
Satoshi white paper and having
confidence that you understand what's
behind the Bitcoin network right that is
more complicated and that that took a
little longer but the move from macro to
gold to Bitcoin that wasn't that um
challenging. It's sort of beyond that
and then really understanding
that Bitcoin and the digital asset world
is really the only interesting thing to
be doing. Like that's another leap.
Are you still holding gold?
Yeah, of course. I mean a long time.
Yeah. And I still have my gold business.
Um, I founded GBI Gold Bullion
International in ' 09, um, with a
partner. That partner is still the CEO
of that business. And, um, last I
checked, we were the third largest var
of gold in the world outside of the
banking system. So, um, that business,
we have vaults in seven different
locations around the world where we
lease space. And, um, you know, it's
chugging along. It just had a record
quarter, I'm sure, with the gold price
doing what it's doing. Um, but yeah, no,
I um I think gold is a very important
hedge for the traditional world. So in
my mind, I see all the traditional
assets, bonds, stocks, currencies,
commodities, um, real estate, everything
that's the traditional world and gold is
in that world. And gold is a hedge
against you know certain macro scenarios
developing. You want to have some gold
in your portfolio in your traditional
portfolio. Bitcoin to me can be thought
of as a hedge against the entire
traditional world including gold in it.
Uh Bitcoin has many many properties. I
don't know if you saw that post Michael
Sailor put out recently the 21
uh uh qualities of Bitcoin. I mean, I
think that's exactly right. I mean,
there are so many uh things that are
driving Bitcoin. Um, but thinking about
it, you know, within that macro
construct as a hedge against everything
in the traditional world, I think if you
thought about that 10 years ago, you've
done very
well, right? Bitcoin as a hedge. You
don't see it as people say a replacement
of gold.
No, I don't think you can replace gold.
I don't think gold's going anywhere. uh
like I don't think the dollar is getting
replaced either. I mean what is it going
to get replaced by you know the the euro
or the yen or the R&B? I mean there's no
way. Um and if if it is if it's being
used less in world trade that makes
sense. Um the dollar is overused in in
you know in certain ways. Um but gold no
gold also think about it this way. Gold
is a physical form uh of store of value.
So if just think about this, I had this
thought a few years ago. If everything
eventually moves on chain, all value and
everything is digitized, then I think
there becomes almost an extreme
demand for something physical that's off
the grid, that's not on chain.
So gold, physical
gold, I I I think as long as we're human
beings and we're analog and we're not
just projections of ourselves like that,
we actually live and move in the world.
And I I don't think gold is is going
away, though.
That sounds like, you know, when when um
CO happened, everyone's online now, so
people crave this in in-person meeting
now. Yeah. Feel like that's the same
logic, right?
It's a very good point. I mean, look,
you flew all the way to New York and you
came to our 50T get together. Yeah, that
was amazing. And well, that was great
that you came. And I I thought that
event was great, the DS event. You know,
when when you get out, I do think these
in-person experiences
uh are going to become more and more
valuable. You get out, you feel the, you
know, the the community, the vibe of the
community. Uh, it's very energetic.
They're, you know, it's very young.
People are on the go. Um, you know, I
think New York ends up just becoming a
massive meeting place, right? I don't
know that you want to live there because
it's it's a bit nutty, but I think as a
place for people to come in and meet
once they finish the you know the
airports and you know fix some of the
infrastructure I um like I think the
next 10 years that becomes something
that's very important to people uh in
their lives m even much more than now.
It was like um I was listening to Elon
Musk yesterday and he was saying, "Oh,
that we're going to have a hundred
billion robots in 10 years or something
like that." He says people are going to
have to start to think about what to do
with all of the time that they have that
like we're approaching some you know
metaphysical moment in human history
where you know the level of wealth and
will be so high that services and goods
will be almost cost almost nothing and
he says the real challenge for people
will be what to do with themselves. So I
think events, again that's a very
roundabout way of saying, but I think
events like the one we were at, you
know, the digital asset summit New York,
those become very valuable. Um, what is
the timeline like? You think in 10 years
we'll have a lot of time or in 20? Don't
you have a lot of time now?
Nope. Nope. No. Okay. Well, um I I I
think he said 10 years. I I think he
just means it'll incrementally change. U
it'll feel a lot different than let's
say 10 years ago,
right? These these changes are big. I
mean AI. So I'll give you an example.
Today I was on a board call for one of
our companies. We've invested in 23
companies. I have 11 board seats um you
know where the firm is represented. And
I I was on a call today and this is a
one of the more complex deeply technical
companies we've invested in. They do API
and node
infrastructure. Okay. Great company.
They're going to do 50 million in
revenue this year. I'm thrilled or more.
uh and they said that the coding that 6
to 12 months ago AI was doing less than
5% of all the coding in the firm and
today it's doing 40%. Wow.
40% like in a
year. So, their costs are dropping big
time because they don't need as many
developers or they repurpose them or
whatever it is. But can you imagine that
40% this is a a big firm successful
important crypto business going from
essentially 0 to 40% of all their coding
needs.
So, I think it's like I was baffled by
that um today just listening to that
call and I think we're thinking we're
going to have to think about that kind
of change and how it impacts us. I mean
I mean every day I just I I'm I still
trying to work through it. I mean even
Elon Musk um and his 100red billion
robots
well okay so if we look at the world
today with things like AI robotic or you
know the market like US debt the tariff
trade war what do you think is one of
the risk or trend opportunity that most
investors are missing I still think that
our space is really underappreciated
appreciated and
underowned.
Um, you know, I I I think Bitcoin I've
never seen anything like this in the
investment world. Normally,
um, and again, I I've been in this world
since the early 90s. Um,
normally
investors, good and bad ones, they tend
to chase performance. M you know that's
people want to own something that does
well and um sometimes that doesn't work
out well for them they buy collapses
they sell whatever it is but for the
most part people's attention increases
when the when the asset does well yes
this asset the Bitcoin and I'll call it
broadly the digital asset ecosystem
lasts 10 12 years is the single best
performing asset in the history of
assets
I mean, there's no financial ass there's
no asset ever that is up as much as
Bitcoin is. It's I don't know tens of
thousands of percent, hundreds of
thousands depending upon where you
start. But the point that I always
highlight to people is that the last 10
years, last 12
years, the NASDAQ, which has done pretty
well, is down
99.9% against Bitcoin.
So if 12 years ago you bought NASDAQ and
you bought Bitcoin, your NASDAQ is down
99% against your Bitcoin position,
right? Because Bitcoin has appreciated
so dramatically.
Normally that would bring a lot of
people people's attention but today you
know the traditional world there's $800
trillion of assets Bitcoin and all the
digital assets all the cryptocurrencies
protocols whatever all of it and all the
equity of the companies in the space is
still only three to four trillion so
it's like three it's it's tiny it's like
4% of total world
assets. It's you you would think that it
that it would I don't know be more
accepted or finally now the Trump
administration I think has brought the
attention level higher. Uh Larry Frink
you know changing his mind on it in the
summer of 23 and bringing the ETF in
January 24. that was a big deal, but
it's still tiny compared to all the
other assets. So, I'm just surprised how
long it's taking. I mean, I was first
introduced to this world in 2012. Um, I
didn't act, you know, immediately. Uh,
and there are a bunch of different
reasons. Uh, I mean, immediately in
significant size, but I I certainly was
aware of it. Um, I had a hard time
convincing myself about certain things.
Here we are. It's like 15 years since
more or 16 years and still there are a
lot of people
who are just not paying attention.
What is holding the institution back?
Because they they can see is the best
performing asset.
Yeah, I I think just, you know, they're
risk averse.
um there's no there's no box to put this
into. That's the problem. It's that it's
and many of those institutional
investors also they're not they don't
invest in currency at all. So they tend
to be US institutions especially stocks
and bonds. Bonds are a dead asset class.
Uh I don't know why anyone would own a
bond 3 4%
uh a year. It just it's not it's not
even worth bothering with it.
Do you think it's safe? I don't think
it's unsafe, but I think your your
purchasing power is getting debased
dramatically against other things. I
think that's really the problem is that
if you look at not just Bitcoin, you can
look at Ethereum or even something like
Ripple which many people don't believe
has validity, but if you take any
cryptocurrency or any business in the
crypto space over the last 10, 12 years
versus anything in the old world, it's
killed it. It's not just Bitcoin. Even
Ripple, NASDAQ is down 99% against
Ripple in the last 10, 12 years. So,
this is a whole new digital asset world,
the digital asset economy, um, that's
growing up from nothing. And I think all
the value will eventually transfer from
the old world and merge into this new
world. I I don't think the old world's
going away. Just like you said, is gold
going to go away? I think you'll have
gold onchain. You do a little bit, but
there's no interest for some reason
there. their interest is is is is small.
Um but yeah, digital I mean a physical
gold isn't going away. Um I don't think
physical real estate is going away, but
I think if you own a lot of real estate,
the purchasing power of that asset is
getting degraded versus all the assets
in the digital world,
right? Because over the next 10 years, I
think Bitcoin can get to a million,
which would be about a 20 trillion
market value, which is not even that
great. That's what gold is today. Um,
it's not even, you know, a fraction.
It's still a fraction of the 800
trillion. So, I'm saying, okay, Bitcoin,
the the best, most liquid store of
value, u best performing asset of all
time. Okay, it goes to it goes up 10
times from today over the next 10 years.
It's not such a big goal. Um, but a
million dollar Bitcoin puts the value at
20 trillion. And I think that real
estate is not going up 10 times. And I
don't think the NASDAQ is going to go up
10 times. Um and then there are other
assets within the digital asset world
that potentially will do even more
because as you know a big chunk of our
world is is venture. there are the core
assets, you know, Bitcoin, ETH, I think
Solana. Um, but, you know, a lot of the
smaller cryptocurrencies eventually just
trend to zero, and they're really more
like venture projects than they are, um,
I would say, you know, assets that will
hold value. See, that's exactly my next
question because in one of your
interviews, you said DeFi revenue has
grown 10x since DeFi summer. 18 months.
18 months, right? In the last 18 months,
DeFi revenue is up. Yeah. 10 times to
230 million in I think it was December
or January. It was only like 25 million
18 months ago. But people are not
talking about it. Like people just don't
care.
I know. I don't get it. Like it's so
funny. I had a call uh just before you
with a sovereign wealth fund, believe it
or not. So you know what part of the
world he's in. and um I put up in our
deck is that chart of the the DeFi
revenue from 2020 till today. And he was
blown away. He says, "I had no idea that
we so far surpassed the 2021 DeFi, you
know, because that was DeFi summer and
there was all this hoopla." But I think
the single biggest month in 21 was like
$13 million of revenue from the biggest
craziest month. He said, "I had no
idea." And the reality is that the
onchain
economy is
growing. It's sort of beneath the radar.
I mean, it doesn't feel beneath the
radar to me, but look, in 2021, there
were zero essentially stable coins. And
last year, we settled over $10 trillion
of stable coins. That's just stable
coins. Then, you know, I just think
you've got the borrow and lend protocols
um in the decentralized world, the yield
protocols. Some of them are bogus, but a
lot of them are not. You know,
a example was small in 2021. It is not
small anymore. You know, the there are
um you know, the dexes have also um
exploded. index volume was almost
non-existent in 2020 2021. Um so just
the the on I just the onchain
economy is kind of booming.
Um but you know what uh I asked my
analyst today I said well why does it
feel doesn't feel as good as it and it
feels good for us. I mean it does our it
feels good for us. It feels really good.
it it's just that it for some reason I
feel that other people don't feel as
good. And then he sent me this chart I
should send to you. It shows that um how
many uh coins have gone to zero that
were issued in this year. And so
unfortunately it looks like so many uh
here's the chart. He says
52.7% of cryptocurrencies have died
since
2021 and in
2025. I'm I'm sorry. Including meme
coins. Yeah. Yeah. It just looks like
there's so many garbage things. Yes. Out
there. I mean, there were garbage things
out there in 2021,
but the number is exponential. And
unfortunately people who aren't
investors um sometimes you know get
caught up in the hype of some project
that's getting promoted or this and
that. That's why I think this regulatory
clarity that the US is hopefully going
to impose is is a good thing because you
know this is the future this world. It's
also a little bit of the wild west and
and it can be a little crazy and I don't
think look people are grown-ups. they
should know what they, you know, they
should know what they're doing. But on
the other
hand, you know, too much fraud and too
much
failure. I think that's one of the
reasons that the space hasn't taken off
more than I would have thought. I mean
even even look we had FTX
um happen and FTX and the Sam Bankman
Freed that whole thing was a nightmare
for many traditional investors who came
in and actually invested in into that
company and he duped a lot of people.
There are a lot of dupers out there in
this space. It's just like any any space
that's new, anytime there's innovation,
like I say often, I feel like I'm a
pioneer heading west in
1840 and there are Indians coming to get
me and you know there there's bad
weather and my, you know, my my horse
dies and you know there's all kinds of
bad stuff that's happening. But on the
other hand, you're out there and you're
settling the new te territory.
So that's a great thing and that just
comes with problems and you're either a
settler pioneer kind of mentality person
or you're not. You know, this is for
entrepreneurs. This is not for, you
know, you want to sit back and flip your
coupon on your bond. That's that's not
for you. But on the other hand, I don't
think everyone should die either. 52%
have died since 21. That's it would just
be nicer if we had some guard rails
where like they had to prove that they
were good or something or you know what
I mean? It wouldn't be terrible if if
there was just some I don't know not a
toll I just some sort of minimum basic
vetting mechanism
somewhere you know you have you have
companies out there you know like chain
analysis
um that vet you know you have companies
like certic that vet you know vetting
it's important to be vetted by somebody
that's good but I bet you many of the
people who are you know super retail
were involved. They don't even know what
a vet a
vetting, you know, would look like,
right? They just hear from a friend that
the friend made 10x and they fomo yolo
into it and it's
like fomo yolo into it and then next
thing you know it's a zero. Um, and you
don't want to see people getting hurt.
That's no fun.
um you know but at the moment it's it's
hard to control because there is a lot
of innovation going on and you don't
want to block that. You don't want to
prevent
that. But um maybe it's just me as an
older guy not wanting to see so many
young people get hurt. The young guys
are like no Dan let it rip. Let you know
let it rip. It's survival of the fittest
out here.
So, well, when you look at a protocol or
a project, how do you form your
investment thesis? Like, how do you tell
good from bad? Yeah. Well, the so far in
our in our fifth fund, we'll be
investing in what I call growth stage
protocols. But in the first four funds
um that I launched, we invested only in
the equity of the more developed
businesses in the space. So I was
looking generally for companies that
were doing or were going to do 40 50
million in revenue. So I was not
investing in those venture projects.
That's that's sort of in a way saved me.
And um for me, a very easy thing that
actually enabled us to pass on over 200
deals in the last few years is just I
want to get in at a reasonable revenue
multiple.
And so one of the reasons that we passed
on FTX three times was that they were
trying to raise capital at a $30 billion
valuation.
um which was you know more than 50 times
revenue. So it's just if how how am I as
an investor going to make any money if I
buy something at a $30 billion valuation
and let's say I want to make a 10x in 10
years that means he's got to go from 30
billion to 300 billion that's very
difficult and there's no room for error
because I'm coming in at 50 times
revenue. So we tend to to only want to
pay it, you know, I don't know, five to
10 times revenue. So for us, something
like FTX was an easy pass. But there are
a lot of easy signs if you do the work.
And I'll give you I'll give you one that
was basic for us, which was that, you
know, if you have a $30 billion company
like he purported to have, you have a
board of you have a board, right? Okay.
So on this board
traditionally would have seven people,
five people, seven people, right? Okay.
How many people did Sam Bankman Freed
have on his FTX board? What's your
guess? None. Okay. Well, no, he had one.
He had one person. He had one person. Do
you want to guess who that one person
was? Um, the ex-girlfriend.
His dad. Oh,
okay. So, let let me just say something.
No, I mean, I I understand there was a
lot of FOMO and hype around him, but
he's the
quintessential, you know, cryptogrifter
person. Um, you know, hyped it up and,
you know, didn't know what they were
doing and all of that other stuff.
People make mistakes, but I think he
went well beyond that. But it was pretty
clear that if you're going to have a a
$30 billion company and you're going to
have a board, if your dad is the only
guy on the board, that's a that's a
pretty big red flag. I think if you talk
to any single equity investor, maybe in
crypto they think that's okay. But um
any investor from the old world would
would be like, whoa, what's going on
here? And the guy is a Stanford
professor, so what does he know about
making money? Um, I just, you know,
there were a lot of red flags or called
them yellow. Um, and look, that being
said, you know, we had two companies um
that we invested in that went to zero. I
never thought I'd have any zeros. It was
less than 5% of our aum, so it didn't
hurt us, but it certainly didn't help
us, and I never thought I'd ever have a
zero, honestly. So, um, you know, it's a
tough space. I think the signs are
easier to read in our in our space that
something is not okay. It's just that
there's so many young people that don't
have, you know, I I just think if you
just use a very simple construct of I'm
going to invest at this thing at $1,
okay, my I'm willing to risk that
$1 because I think let's say over the
next five years that $1 can go to
$10. That's a good riskreward. I'm going
to risk one. And if you you know I'm
going to create a scenario. I'm going to
build a model. I'm going to write an
investment memo that explains why I
think the asset can go up 10 times over
the next 10 years. And I'm going to do
traditional cash flow analysis. I'm
going to do all the analysis. You could
put it into AI now. probably just dump
your whole thought into Grock and he'll
come out with a nice, you know,
explanation of what the investment is
and, you know, whether you should do it
or not or whatever it is. Um, but I I
think I think that's really the issue is
that people were not doing their
homework
um in in the 21 cycle. I think that's
what led to a lot of, you know, some of
those higher profile blowups in the
venture space. I don't know. I think
it's pretty much like Vegas, you know,
it's like Las Vegas. I mean, it's not
it's just some of that is just pure
gambling.
Um that being said, look the the core uh
technology and the core value principles
behind Bitcoin I think are the most
important you know developments in the
history of money. Um and value I as I
said I think all things of value are
going to be represented on some
blockchain somewhere. I think even
within 10 years, you're going to see all
of these old world assets tokenized.
You're going to see things on chain
that, you know, are hard to value that
people don't, you know, the all of the,
you know, music uh rights and all of
those, you know, social things, all the
blockchain gaming I think is going to be
still huge. It's taking time to develop,
but
um yeah, you have a company out there,
Anamoka, that I think is sort of at the
forefront uh in that you invested in
them, right? Yes, I did. No, you did,
too. No. Oh, okay. I did. Yes. Full
disclosure, I did. We did. Yes. And um
Okay. So, you have different funds. The
first one was 10 trillion 10T because
you thought in 2019 when the crypto
market was 300 billion, you think it was
going to grow to um 10 trillion in 10
years and now you have a 50T. Yes. Where
we are right on track. We're on track.
Correct. I I I can't believe it. I it
was my view and I spent a lot of time
thinking about it and I thought no one
will ever believe me five or 10 years
from now so I have to put that into the
name of the fund for you know to stamp
it. Yes. And now 50T.
Yes. Tell me the rationale behind the
number because US stock market is 50T
right? 50T is our fifth fund now. I said
I think we got Bitcoin going to 20 uh T
in 10 years. So that's um a 10x from
today in 10 years. Some people in the
Bitcoin world would call that bearish
that I'm negative, but I think that's a
reasonable estimate. Um then another 10
trillion for all of the non Bitcoin
cryptocurrencies.
Mhm. So then I get 30 and then I think
there'll be 20 trillion dollars of
digital asset
ecosystem crypto blockchain web 3 equity
or businesses that are
onchain that maybe the value is
represented by a token maybe there's
equity maybe there's some hybrid model
so I think the digital asset economy the
value there is 20 so I add 20 and 10
that's 50 and I think
that's you know that's still only uh you
know 6% really 7% right if there's 800
trillion um and if you assume okay those
assets go up in 10 years to uh a th000
trillion then we're 50T is only 5%. So
10 years from now, it's it's a
conservative call because how
can how could we only have 5% of the
world's assets digitized in 10 years
from now? It seems like it seems like
it's too conservative a call, but 10T is
going to end up being too conservative
as well. I I tend to be a little
conservative in my in my nature. I mean
I I do I'm not I'm not a venture guy.
I'm not trying to make a 100x returns uh
you know or you know choosing some super
speculative token right so the next big
topic would be real world asset because
you said everything will be on chain but
um I think retail investors have a very
hard time imagining what that world
would look like. What do you mean I can
buy real estate or gold on chain? What
does that really mean? So, at the
moment, it doesn't mean anything because
it's still early and people and people
aren't doing it really yet. Um, I think
there's partial buy in, you know, I I um
from the traditional world, but there's
not full buy in. Um I I also think
there's some place where the old sort of
banking rails and payment rails need to
collide with
DeFi. And I think that the user
experience in DeFi is not great. It's
very complex.
Um, you know, I I think even even like
some of my young guys on my team who are
super active in DeFi all day long, I
think sometimes when they, you know, I I
don't want to say push the send button,
but I think there's a moment there when
they, you know, send something
crosschain where they're a little
nervous. Yeah. Right. And so,
Right. So we have to move to a place
where that goes away. So if the dgens
are nervous like some guy at a big bank
in you know Taipei or in New
York, he's going to be 10x more nervous.
And so that just slows things down.
So the the reason I think there there's
value for things to everything to be on
chain is that we'll have one unified
place where value can become
fungeable. So that's the that's the
mystery here to unlock all of the value
in these illquid assets. I mean real
estate is hundreds of trillions but
there's real value there. Now how do you
analyze them? How do you put them on
chain? How does that work? Well, it's
happening slowly. I mean, gold, there's
Pax Gold, my friend at at Paxos, they've
got they've had that product forever,
but it hasn't taken off
um in a way that you would have thought
when they released it. I think that's
because the average age of your gold
investor is like
75 literally and the average age of your
you know DeFi DGEN is like 30 and they
don't want gold
but I think it's time and
convergence right I as I said I don't
think the old world is going away I just
think the two are converging
um but you know maybe we'll have our you
know, you know, they called Netscape
moment or our, you know, our chat GPT
moment. I mentioned you that company
today went from zero
uh to 40% in terms of the code being
written by AI. So, we're still waiting
for that. I mean, the existence of
Coinbase, I think, has been tremendous.
Uh, you know, as a public company that
people look up to that does what they
say they're going to do. I know they're
all, you know, people always have
complaints, etc., But um I think we need
to get some of the proper businesses,
the more developed
projects, think we need to get them into
a framework where capital can be
invested into them. So when Trump and
the US administration says they're going
to make the US the crypto hub of the
world, I think the best way really to do
that is to encourage the legitimate
companies to list on NASDAQ. and NYC all
of globally even the foreign ones that's
how you make the US the hub you have 40
or 50 companies like Coinbase not like
Coinbase but you know crypto blockchain
businesses and I think that helps with
credibility and then it's those
companies that have access to all that
traditional old world capital that also
then can go in and innovate in the space
I mean look at what Coinbase has done
with Bass that is
mindboggling. 3 years ago, would we have
said that they were going to launch an
L2? I mean, no way. They're they're
basically the gateway to DeFi now,
right? Mhm. I mean, I'm asking you,
would you Yeah, I was I'm and I'm
surprised at at how it's taken
off. Um, not unexpectedly.
A lot of companies are going public,
right?
Well, they would like to um Okay, the I
think E Toro is in the hopper. Um I
think Circle has uh it's been out there
at some point in the next few months. I
think Figure has been discussed. I think
next year uh Kraken potentially could be
listed. But I think if we make if we
create an environment in the US that is
encouraging for companies crypto
blockchain companies to list. I think
that helps with that rubber stamp that
is missing in the space
right this is we talked about this you
know 15 20 minutes ago. I I do. And
again, I'm from the traditional world
originally, so maybe I'm
overemphasizing that. Um, and all the
super DGEN guys are like, damn, that's
the old world. There's going to be no
equity. They're only going to be tokens.
Everything is it it just it's not going
to work that way. There's too much value
that's been built up in the old world.
They've been building value in that
world for thousands of years. Yes. Yes.
I mean, think about art, you know, think
about old master
paintings. Old master paintings have
been considered a store of value for 500
year. I mean, you know, since beginning
of time, but I'm just saying, think
about, you know, the last 500 years. If
you made a certain amount of money and
you were looking to store your wealth,
um, 200, 300 years ago, you you bought a
piece of art. I mean you people do that
now. I mean you do lots of things. You
have real estate, you have bonds, you
have arts. So just think about all the
value that's accured in that world over
the thousand years. It's not going to
move on chain in one day, right? Like
the So you ask me like real world asset
tokenization. It it's it's a process.
Um, and I think it's largely defined,
unfortunately, by age, which which is to
say that the younger people all will
make it happen. The older people, I
think, are resistant. But I think a lot
of people are like, why do we need to
move that onchain? Because we already
have them at home. We already have them,
you know, in a vault, in a safe. Why on
Jane? Because for most of the assets
that they own which are illquid, they
become fungeable with all their other
assets. They're also a lot safer in in
my view. It's a lot safer. Someone can
come into your house and
just rob you. True. True.
Uh, you know, I I guess if you have your
value on a ledger and they I guess they
could rob you then, too. But, uh, they'd
have to know your, you
know, private key. I mean, I don't know
how you you know, I don't I don't know
how that'll work
um in the future.
[Music]
Um, but yeah, I I think if you're just,
you know, moving around in DeFi all day,
you you maybe don't have any value
that's in the old world. I'm saying if
the goal is the
US is going to become the global crypto
blockchain hub, how do you do
that? Right? And I think just making an
environment amendable for programmers to
come and develop new code off of new
chains and this and that, that's great.
But that's not it. It's about how to get
the $800
trillion that's
there digitized.
Are they doing that now? You think? Does
the government see it that way? Maybe a
little bit. I I think that they will see
it this way. I think that actually if
you look at the progress that's been
made over the last five years, I would
argue that they see it that way. And I
think the thing that's really driving
them though, I mean that they really get
is the stable coin.
Uh and the the the fact that 99% of all
stable coins are dollar based. this
tremendous desire and need for dollars
um overseas that it really is the
banking the unbanked you know many of
the emerging market uh countries that
don't have access to a bank that you
have access to to to dollars via stable
coins I think owning the stable coin
market
uh is important for the US government
and it may it makes sense and people say
oh because it allows them to fund their
treasuries
easier. I I think that's nonsense. Um
the US is not having difficulty funding
its US treasuries. I I think if you look
at the future, you want to be in the
middle of the most liquid, deepest
market.
Um I don't want to say you want to
control it, but you want to be involved
with it, right? And I think the US
government if you control it, I mean the
US is not as intense about controlling
everything because it stifles
innovation. Um but where we were a year
ago, like everyone in the space was was
being attacked, right? The SEC was
suing, I don't know, eight or nine
prominent uh companies and now those
suits are all dropped.
So, you know, I I think that, you know,
when you say to me, do they, you know,
is the government is the government is
this sort of their thoughts? I think if
you look at where they were and where
they are today, you could argue that
they do see this bigger picture of all
value moving on chain. But the most
important
thing to move on chain first is their
money. of course the dollars. Yeah, that
make a lot of sense. Yeah. So,
and look, I think it's a huge benefit.
Look, I I I always bring come back to
this that the internet was the
digitization of ideas and
information. And right now, uh, you
know, Bitcoin and this digital asset
world, we're digitizing value and money.
So that's got to be the biggest
investment theme of all time, right? If
you thought the internet was big, this
has got to be bigger from an investment
perspective. So if you want to figure
out like what is the TAM, total
addressable market,
like why do I think 50T why are we why
do we have the 50T
fund? Because I do my the math. We model
it
out and I come up with 50T and then I
talk with you and it sounds like I'm
conservative because that's only going
to be
5% of you know the total world out there
and it's already 50T. So that's very
very encouraging.
Yeah. Well, the view is that it will be
50T. It's 4T today. Um, in terms of the
total value, um, but I I I
um I think 10 years from now, if only 5%
of value is
digitized, that seems too low, right?
I'm talking there'll be a because
they're 800 trillion in 10 years
there'll be a thousand trillion.
What's a like you think it's more you
think it's too conservative. So what is
your new number? No, there that's the
number I'm sticking with. I'm going to
stay with that. I I think I think 50T is
a number that has a a very strong
probability of happening. Just like I I
thought 10T was a strong probability. I
remember early on when I said that,
there were guys certainly on Twitter who
were saying to me, "Look, you're way too
low on your 10T estimate." Like, that's
cute. That's that's funny. That's nice.
Um, and maybe they'll end up being
right. Um, but I think as an investor,
if you're looking
for, you know, what is what is a good
investment in the future that will
preserve your purchasing
power, right? Sailor says often that
Bitcoin is a savings technology. I love
that framework that he use he uses. I I
I really believe that and I think if you
expand a little bit from Bitcoin, if you
can't be 100% into Bitcoin, you see that
the entire digital asset world
um especially the core assets, Ethereum,
Salana has appreciated to a similar
degree. Even Ripple, when I first bought
Ripple the first time, it was onetenth
of one penny. Wow. Onetenth of one
penny. And it was so much fun to trade.
You w on there on their system and you
could drive the price up with like a
$50,000 $100,000 purchase. It was fun.
But you could like drive the price up
and you know you go from onetenth of one
penny to one and a half ten of one
penny. And today it's $2. That's
Ripple. So and Ripple even in our world
people think is questionable.
So just imagine if the if the
questionable
asset is
up what tens of thousands
percent.
Um I mean that's just mindboggling. You
just don't you don't hear people talk
about it in this way.
I don't know why. Do you have time for
one more question? I know you have to
go. Yeah. Uh, I do and we can do this
again. I mean, I'm surprised how cogent
I am at what is it 9:30 at night. One
last question because um a lot of young
people watch this show and everyone's
like chasing profit. People are trying
to make it, right? But what is one
philosophy in life that you hold true to
and that you live by? Uh, visav
investments or like even something more
like deeply philosophical
just in life. Um.
Mhm.
I would
say uh I mean there's so many of them
actually. Uh I I have a I used to write
I mean I have so many of these like
little sayings and little things I do.
But at the core of everything I would
say is you know enjoy the the discipline
of your process. Yeah. That's that's
like my whole life. Uh if you enjoy the
discipline of your
process. Uh you'll be successful in
anything that you do. You know, I I was
going to some people say, "Oh, stay
curious." Yeah, I mean, stay curious is
great. Yeah, of course you have to stay
curious. Um but nothing will ever get
done if you don't
have you know you don't
enjoy that
rigor you know the the
discipline of your analytical for me
it's my analytical process
um
because well that's at the end of the
day I don't want to overstate this but
like I mean that is what your art
is as a human
being. So if you think that the creative
function is the most important function
of a human being, then enjoying the
discipline of getting that art out has
to be the purpose of your life. When you
say
discipline, are we talking about the
discipline that everyone think like
getting up early and like the routine or
stick to something
or you know it it can be whatever your
process is. So you have a podcast and
you you know you have a set number of
podcasts that you like to do every day,
every week. You have a so if you do that
for days and weeks and months and years
and years that you begin to have a
process and that process exists because
you've applied your discipline to it and
you've made it repeatable. But I'm
saying you have to
enjoy applying your the discipline to
your process and if you really enjoy it
uh then everything is gravy like for me
it's been that way in the investment
business coming up with new ideas. Uh
but you also have to believe that the
creative function is the most important
one.
Uh, and I remember this great book I
read many years ago by Albert Kimu
called The Rebel, which is a history of
it's it's not really it's it's really a
history of the creative
uh power in you know in the west and I
guess it could be applied to the whole
world but this is it's more of a
history. Um it's a phenomenal book that
I doubt any I mean very few people could
make it through that book. It was
a phenomenal book. Um, but really
complex. That's the stuff I used to
study. So, you study history and
philosophy, right? And philosophy in
college. I didn't do economics or uh
business or math or any of that ever. I
was I was not very good at math
actually. Um, for some reason I just
But you're very good with life.
Well, I hope so. Thank you. Uh, that's
an observation that you have. Um, I
would say I'm not bad with life, but
thank you. That's a very powerful
ending. Thank you for that. And, um,
please come back soon. Yeah. Anytime you
like.